YASH ANAND

Software Engineer

A passion for web applications, programming languages, and computer systems, with a track record of delivering high-quality solutions for both enterprise and product-based startups. Master's from a top CS school, with experience that spans researching WebAssembly, as well as designing and implementing kernels and optimizing compilers.

HONORS

Director's Scholarship Carnegie Mellon Univ. (2022)

Special Recognition Award Shell (2022)

VP CIO Award Shell (2021)

Service Recognition Award Shell (2021)

EDUCATION

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

Master of Software Engineering Carnegie Mellon University, School of CS CGPA: 3.9/4 • Pittsburgh, PA, U.S.A

Aug 2015 - May 2019

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology Vellore Institute of Technology CGPA: 8.5/10 • Vellore, India

Coursework (CMU)

Operating System Design and Implementation, Compiler Design, Software Architecture, Web Applications, Advanced Formal Methods, Intro to Computer Systems

Experience (CMU)

Teaching Assistant for Web Applications Teaching Assistant for Software Architecture

EXPERIENCE

Apr 2024 - Present

Software Engineer Cedana

Pittsburgh, USA (Remote)

Jul 2019 - Jul 2022

Software Engineer

Shell Bangalore, India (On-site)

Sep 2018 - Jul 2019

Lead Software Developer

Vicara

Vellore, India (Part-time)

Engineering across the kernel and networking stack, to unlock performance on the cloud through flexible checkpoint/resume/migrate for CPU and GPU workloads. Improved the cold start time (time-to-first-token) for several large language models (LLM) by 10x. Devel a state-of-the-art benchmark suite integrated with the CI for monitoring regressions.

Optimized load time of org-wide skills and resource management applications by 70%. Pioneered a CI/CD initiative for the platform, and implemented mission-critical software for managing projects, resources, and security incidents across the organization. Winner of org-wide VP CIO Award in May 2021, and Service Recognition Awards.

Solely developed the desktop user interface for a wearable gesture controller called Kai. Lead software team for a product that raised over \$100k via crowdfunding on Indiagogo. While simultaneously pursuing an undergraduate degree, built the entire web eco-system including UI component libraries, product website, auth intermediary, and many more.

PROJECTS

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

Pebbles Kernel & Hypervisor C, x86 Assembly

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

WASM Dynamic Analysis WebAssembly, Rust, Virgil

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

C Compiler

OCaml, x86, WebAssembly

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

Dynamic Memory Allocator C, Linux

Carnegie Mellon • 2022

Chesster

JavaScript, Python, Django

[Link] Implemented a Unix-like kernel for x86 with a robust user thread library, loader, drivers, with preemptive multitasking, multi-threading, demand paging, Copy-on-Write. Type 1 hypervisor capable of running guest kernels, with support for virtual consoles.

[**Link**] Developed dynamic analysis and instrumentation tools for a WebAssembly engine. Submitted a paper to ASPLOS titled "Flexible Non-intrusive Dynamic Instrumentation for WebAssembly" evaluating several well-known techniques against our novel design.

Designed and constructed a memory-safe optimizing compiler for a subset of the Clanguage achieving runtime performance on par with the industry-standard GCC (-01). Features included strings, function pointers, arrays, structs, and a WebAssembly target.

Implemented a high-performance dynamic memory allocator surpassing the efficiency of C's standard malloc package for a diverse set of program traces. Achieved rank 1 performance & utilization in 15213 summer '23 class of 150 students.

[Link] Built a fully-functional online chess multiplayer game that featured in-game spectators, live chat, and a global live feed of top-spectated games. Uses vanilla JavaScript and WebSockets for all it's complex asynchronous interactions.

Top Skills Languages C C++

JavaScript x86 Assembly WebAssembly **OCaml** Python

Tools/Technologies Vim React Angular Diango